leaguetoolbox.com 2012-05-03

# LeagueToolbox - League Management Software Update 2012 - Privacy Policy

As a leader in the provision of Internet-related services, LeagueToolbox is committed to building trust and confidence in our members use of our services and the Internet by promoting our use of fair information practices. 

The continued rise of Internet use has brought a lot of concern about privacy and the security of information to the forefront of public debate. 

LeagueToolbox is committed to ensuring your privacy, and has kept up to date with recent guidelines and discussions that pertain to the collection, use and disclosure of this information. In addition, our services incorporate sophisticated security measures, including software developed for this specific purpose, to ensure that your confidential information is protected. In order to protect your privacy, please do not tell anyone your password. 

We have created this privacy policy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. Personal information within our control will be governed by the fair information principles embodied in the Canadian Standards Association (CSA) Model Code for the Protection of Personal Information. This Standard is based on a set of principles internationally recognized for the protection of personal information in both the public and private sector, and has now become a schedule to the Personal Information and Electronic Documents Act of Canada. 

Please read the Privacy Policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our services. Our fair information principles are noted directly below. By clicking on one of the links that follow, you will find specific examples of the types of information that will be collected by LeagueToolbox and how it will be used. This policy statement may change from time to time, and we will post all changes on this page so that you can check back periodically to review them. 

Fair Information Principles

**Accountability**

LeagueToolbox is responsible for the information under its control, and has designated an individual or individuals who are accountable for our compliance with these principles, and to any policies adopted. 

**Knowledge and Consent**

LeagueToolbox informs members and other users, in advance, about the collection, use, disclosure, retention and disposal of personal information. 

**Collection of Information**

The collection of personal information will be limited to that which is necessary for the purposes identified by LeagueToolbox, and all information will be collected by fair and lawful means. 

**Use, Disclosure and Retention**

Personal information is not used or disclosed by LeagueToolbox for purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with the expressed consent of our members or as required by law. LeagueToolbox will only use and disclose personal information about members to unrelated third parties after the member has been informed in advance of the possibility of such use and disclosure, and has provided consent. Personal information is retained only as long as is necessary for the fulfillment of those purposes or as required by law. 

**Accuracy**

LeagueToolbox executes accurate record keeping procedures. Members are also encouraged to provide accurate information when using the service. Information previously provided can also be or modified at any time by members through the web site. 

**Safeguards**

LeagueToolbox has developed procedures to safeguard members' personal information, appropriate to the sensitivity of the information provided. This includes protecting the access to, use, disclosure, retention and disposal of personal information. 

**Openness**

LeagueToolbox will readily make available information about its policies and practices relating to the management of personal information. 

**Member Access**

Upon request, any member will be informed of the existence, use and disclosure of his or her personal information, and will be given access to that information. 

**Members Come First**

LeagueToolbox recognizes the interest and concerns of the member in developing privacy and information management principles. LeagueToolbox remains flexible in responding to changing member needs and expectations regarding privacy as our service continues to evolve. 

If you have any questions about this privacy statement or the practices of this site you can contact us at anytime by clicking "Contact Us" on our homepage. 

**Types of Information Collected**

As a member using the LeagueToolbox Services, it is important for you to know that each time our service is used two types of information may be collected. 

1\. Statistical Information: Statistics on an aggregate basis are collected each time members browse, register, or access services or information from our site. 

2\. Personal information: Personal information collected is provided by the member, and may include username, passwords, and identifying information such as name, address, and phone number, where this information is required to register for certain programs or events. Personal Information You Choose to Share 

Throughout the LeagueToolbox site, you may have the opportunity to send e-mails, request information, create personal web pages, register for programs or events, participate in online surveys or contests and other promotions sponsored by us. If you choose to participate, you may be providing LeagueToolbox with some type of personal information. 

You can be assured that if you choose to provide any personal information to us, LeagueToolbox will use it only for the purposes specified or intended. For example, if you register for a tournament and specify your name, address and other billing information, LeagueToolbox will not use this for any other purpose than to process your registration. 

LeagueToolbox will share information with the organizations for which you are registering for the purpose of completing the registration process. 

LeagueToolbox will also share information with governmental authorities when legally required to do so, and may cooperate with such authorities investigating claims of illegal activity such as (but not limited to) illegal transfer of copyrighted material, or user website postings or email messages that contain threats of violence. Other than these specific exceptions noted, we do not sell, rent or provide access to any data collected about or from our members 

LeagueToolbox incorporates a multi-layered security model to ensure the protection of all communications on our web site and between members. This technology, when combined with good security policies and common sense, makes LeagueToolbox a secure and trustworthy tool for your use. 

**Links to Other Sites & Third Party Content**

This site contain may contain links to other sites in order to enhance your online experience or to supplement the information that you provide. This information may be received from our partners or other information providers in sponsored content sections. 

When you leave LeagueToolbox the privacy statements of these third parties will apply. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. 

Our intention is to provide a safe, fun and dynamic environment, and should you find a link on our site that you feel is inappropriate, do not hesitate to contact us immediately. 

**More About Privacy & Protection of Information**

As part of an industry that deals with sensitive information, LeagueToolbox recognizes the importance of member privacy. Most efforts at legislating privacy begin with "Fair Information Practices", which are sets of privacy principles. Fair information practices are guidelines for the collection, use, disclosure, retention and disposal of personal information. These practices are the cornerstone of most efforts to protect personal information around the world. These guidelines have been widely adopted. Their influence can be seen in the laws that govern the public sector federally, as well as provincially in Canada. 

In the early 90's, the Canadian Standards Association (CSA) gathered representatives from the public, private sector industries, advocacy groups and unions, to discuss the need for a common code to protect personal information in the private sector. The outcome of the initiative was the development of the Model Code for the Protection of Personal Information, which represents a consensus among all stakeholders. Based on the OECD guidelines, the Code addresses the way in which organizations collect, use, disclose and protect personal information, and the right of individuals to access personal information about themselves and to have the information corrected if necessary. 

The Standards Council of Canada adopted the CSA Code as a National Standard in 1996, making Canada the first country in the world to adopt such a Standard. In May of 1996, the member policy group of the International Organization for Standardization (ISO) passed a unanimous, 25-country resolution in favor of a proposal to develop an international standard on privacy based on the CSA Standard. 

More recently, the CSA Model Code has become a schedule to the Personal Information and Electronic Documents Act of Canada. 

For additional information on Privacy & Protection of Information, contact: 

Industry Canada Task Force on Electronic Commerce  
Privacy@ic.gc.ca  
CAN/CSA-Q830-96 Model Code for the Protection of Personal Information  
(the CSA Standard)

1980 Guidelines on the Protection of Privacy and Transborder Flows of Personal Data, developed by the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), and abridged version 

The federal Privacy Act 

The Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada
